<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Nate Agrin</title>
 <link href="http://www.n8agrin.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.n8agrin.com/"/>
 <updated>2012-01-18T09:31:10-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.n8agrin.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Nate Agrin</name>
   <email>nate@n8agrin.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Apple's iCloud Potential</title>
   <link href="http://www.n8agrin.com/2011/06/04/Apple%27s-iCloud-Potential.html"/>
   <updated>2011-06-04T23:57:00Z</updated>
   <id>http://www.n8agrin.com/2011/06/04/Apple's-iCloud-Potential</id>
   <content type="html">I've long wondered what Apple might be doing with their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tuaw.com/2011/06/01/apples-north-carolina-data-center-now-visible-on-google-earth/&quot;&gt;massive North Carolina data center&lt;/a&gt;. There's the obvious: cloud music hosting. But what else could Apple do with that much storage and also possibly execute on better than any other company in existence?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ubiquitous_computing&quot;&gt;Ubiquitous computing&lt;/a&gt;. Or at least the first few steps in that direction. What if they come up with a way to integrate all of your Mac devices together? Your iMac is aware of your iPhone which is aware of your Macbook Pro which is aware of your iPad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Imagine waking up, reading part of a nytimes.com article on your iMac, but having to leave in the middle of it to catch the train to work. You take with you your iPad which, when you open it, already has the nytimes.com page you were reading loaded in Safari.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the kind of thing Apple could pull off with a proper cloud service. Never mind wifi syncing of your iPhone to iTunes, that would just be the tip of the iceberg.&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2578204452090821798-5068472936853491665?l=n8agrin.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>You only get one life</title>
   <link href="http://www.n8agrin.com/wordsiwishiwrote/2011/02/23/You-only-get-one-life.html"/>
   <updated>2011-02-23T05:41:00Z</updated>
   <id>http://www.n8agrin.com/wordsiwishiwrote/2011/02/23/You-only-get-one-life</id>
   <content type="html">Found via Twitter:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;You only get one life. No receipt, no proof of purchase. You can't&lt;br /&gt;take it back to the shops if bored. Hence the fact that you should&lt;br /&gt;appreciate what you've got. Find a job you love, find people you love,&lt;br /&gt;visit your grandparents and get to the seaside as often as possible.&lt;br /&gt;Eat well and eat cake. Go running, go jumping. Get your five a day.&lt;br /&gt;Laugh. Feed the cat. Fix your bike. Have a baby and smoke a cigar.&lt;br /&gt;Camp in the woods, bake some bread and buy a trampoline.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;via: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/reybango/status/40151402412126208&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/#!/reybango/status/40151402412126208&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2578204452090821798-7981188746256501479?l=n8agrin.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Desiderata</title>
   <link href="http://www.n8agrin.com/wordsiwishiwrote/2011/02/23/Desiderata.html"/>
   <updated>2011-02-23T04:44:00Z</updated>
   <id>http://www.n8agrin.com/wordsiwishiwrote/2011/02/23/Desiderata</id>
   <content type="html">I found the following in a hostel on the South Island of New Zealand. It's sat in my journal for years, but is worth sharing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Desiderata:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Go placidly amid the noise and haste and remember what peace there may be in silence. As far as possible without surrender, be on good terms with all persons. Speak your truth quietly and clearly; and listen to others - even the dull and ignorant; they too have their story. Avoid loud and aggressive persons; they are vexations to the spirits.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you compare yourself with others, you will become vain and bitter - for always there will be greater and lesser persons than yourself. Enjoy your achievements as well as your plans.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Keep interested in your own career, however humble; it is a real possession in the changing fortunes of time. Exercise caution in your business affairs for the world is full of trickery. But let this not blind you to what virtue there is, many persons strive for high ideals; and everywhere life is full of heroism.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;BE YOURSELF. Especially do not feign affection. Neither be cynical about love; for in the face of all aridity and disenchantment it is perennial as the grass. Take kindly the counsel of the years, gracefully surrendering the things of youth. Nurture strength of spirit to shield you in sudden misfortune. DO NOT DISTRESS YOURSELF WITH IMAGININGS. Many fears are born of fatigue and loneliness. Beyond a wholesome discipline, be gentle with yourself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You are a child of the Universe, no less than the trees and the birds. You have a right to be here. And whether or not it is clear to you, no doubt the Universe is unfolding as it should. Therefore be at peace with God, whatever you conceive &quot;Him&quot; to be, and whatever your labors and aspirations, in the noisy confusion of life, keep peace with your soul. With all its sham, drudgery and broken dreams; it is still a beautiful world. BE CAREFUL. STRIVE TO BE HAPPY.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Supposedly this was written by Max Ehrmann. This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessballs.com/desideratapoem.htm&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; has more about it.&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2578204452090821798-8642731648642893104?l=n8agrin.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Twitter Hackweek Project Dead Simple Meetups aka What's the Happs?</title>
   <link href="http://www.n8agrin.com/2010/12/30/My-Twitter-Hackweek-Project%3A-Dead-Simple-Meetups-aka-What%27s-the-Happs%3F.html"/>
   <updated>2010-12-30T19:33:00Z</updated>
   <id>http://www.n8agrin.com/2010/12/30/My-Twitter-Hackweek-Project:-Dead-Simple-Meetups-aka-What's-the-Happs?</id>
   <content type="html">At the end of October, Twitter held a &lt;a href=&quot;http://engineering.twitter.com/2010/10/hack-week.html&quot;&gt;hackweek&lt;/a&gt;, this is the general idea I worked on for the week which I called &quot;What's the Happs?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Elevator pitch:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Imagine you want to go for a bike ride in an hour and want find someone to ride with, or maybe you are looking for a place to watch a baseball game in the afternoon because you don't have a television. There currently is no good way of finding what people are doing nearby and soliciting an audience for company. What's the Happs is a quick way of broadcasting to a mass audience what you're planning on doing in the near future and finding out if anyone would like to join you, or finding out what's happening nearby and meeting up with someone. Think meetup.org meets Twitter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why work on this?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was new to Twitter at the time, and a lot of the projects being kicked around seemed either to be obviously on the roadmap or not really off in left field enough for me. I felt like hackweek was an opportunity to work on something completely different, inspired of course, by the creation of Twitter from Odeo's hackweek. After trying to devise some ideas of my own, I solicited the advice of my friend Kevin (@k7lim) and asked him if he had full access to all the resources at Twitter, what would he build. He outlined an idea he had been playing with that was effectively the ability to ask a broad audience to meetup and do things together in the very near future. This idea became What's the Happs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 0 - how What's the Happs got implemented in Twitter:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I implemented What's the Happs to be simply a new Tweet type. Just as you create a direct message today using the &quot;d&quot; prefix before the text of your Tweet, I created a &quot;w&quot; prefix which would shuttle the tweet into a What's the Happs queue. For example: &quot;w Headed off to China Camp to go mountain biking at 3pm, company welcome.&quot; These What's the Happs Tweets would appear in the right dashboard panel of the new Twitter layout, based on your geolocation and the original geolocation of the What's the Happs Tweet author. The idea was that you could then click on these Tweets and see conversations around the mini-event.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This ended up being pretty much a major failure in my eyes. First of all, the experience wasn't compelling it all. It was unclear why you'd even want to see these weird Tweets from people you didn't follow, but were geographically near you in your home dashboard. Second, there was no way to really search over all the nearby What's the Happs tweets so there was no way to get more of what was happening in the world around you outside of the 4 or 5 Tweets I displayed. There was also no way to dismiss these Tweets if they didn't have any interest for you. A lot of the failure to implement the feature more completely was my own fault. I ended up working alone in a development environment I had only had about a month's experience on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 1 - What I'd like What's the Happs to be:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ok, but really what am I trying to accomplish with What's the Happs and how is it not Twitter, Facebook, Foursquare, Meetup etc? At it's core, WTH is about publishing what you're going to do in the near future to a mass audience, not just people who follow you. I think this is where it differentiates itself from Twitter. It's also meant to be noncommittal. You shouldn't have to publish an event by filling out a big form nor should you have or expect to have many people necessarily show up. To me this is how it differentiates itself from Meetup and Facebook Events. It should be highly mobile. You should be able to publish something like &quot;I'm looking for a place to watch the game tonight, anyone have a TV?&quot; and then decide to move on to a bar and still receive updates on your phone from people who are also interested in your post so you can update them on your change of plan. Foursquare let's you approximate this with checkins, but Foursquare is decidedly about location and the now and not about what you're doing in the near future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Considering these thoughts, I ended up believing that it was a mistake to attempt to integrate the What's the Happs idea into Twitter itself. Instead I probably should have tried to make it its own service.  In this way it could build on top of Twitter, Meetup and Foursquare, leveraging those services to help people communicate, remain geo aware and plan lightweight events happening soon but not right now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To me, the minimum viable product is a simple service you can create an identity on and publish these lightweight events into loose categories. The categories should be searchable by geographic location. Each posting should have a sort of conversation view so you can see who's joining and get more information about particulars of an event. Perhaps each user could have an identity and other individuals could up-vote the mini events, giving users reputations. Beyond this minimal idea, it would be interesting to integrate into all the services mentioned previously in order to provide a broader reach into other communities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fin&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Personally, I would love to have a service like this. I often drive to Tahoe, surf and bike alone knowing that there are probably hundreds of people doing the same things or interested in the same things who I haven't yet had the serendipity to meet. I have little reservation in admitting that this idea is a long shot and possibly violates some core social norms (meeting strangers, trust, etc) which might ultimately make it fail. But I could also imagine it being incredibly successful. For one, it might fit into an interesting niche as almost an informal dating service allowing people to meet based on interest in a noncommittal way. Or I could see it being picked up by people looking for quick groups to form up, like cyclists who are already part of a cycling group looking for new members, someone looking to get a basketball game going, or people wanting to create some kind of flash mob.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We live in a brave new world, where our perceptions of what's normal in society are rapidly changing. Maybe, as crazy as it might sound, it's time for something like What's the Happs?&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2578204452090821798-3168318987013389872?l=n8agrin.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>One Whole Year Ago</title>
   <link href="http://www.n8agrin.com/2005/10/18/One-Whole-Year-Ago.html"/>
   <updated>2005-10-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.n8agrin.com/2005/10/18/One-Whole-Year-Ago</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;One Whole Year Ago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;October 18, 2005 &amp;#8211; Fairfax, VA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One whole year ago&amp;#8230; One year ago I was stepping off a plane and into a world I never thought I would see. One year ago I packed my winter clothes in my closet, my summer close in a backpack, and headed to the other side of the world. One year ago, and it feels like just yesterday. I literally remember specifics about my first day in New Zealand, and can recall the sequence of initial events; the alien vegetation on the way from the airport, meeting Ben in the hostel, and finding great espresso in a foreign city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week my one year, once-in-a-lifetime visa to live and work freely in New Zealand expired.  It would be untruthful to say that I was not upset by that fact.  Dishonest to think I didn’t romance the ideas of what could have been had I stayed the winter there. Where would i be now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a certain degree I regret coming home. I miss the wandering lifestyle, my crappy car, my surfboards, the sand in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/n8agrin/69862001/in/set-1504232/&quot;&gt;bed&lt;/a&gt;, the cold hard ground of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/n8agrin/71368215/in/set-1504232/&quot;&gt;tent&lt;/a&gt;, driving around with two people and so much stuff you couldn’t see out the back door.  I miss &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/n8agrin/69861850/in/set-1504232/&quot;&gt;kiteboarding with Sean&lt;/a&gt; and asking Phil for a wetsuit. I miss the views from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.solscape.co.nz/&quot;&gt;Solscape&lt;/a&gt;, and the people I met there. I miss the Coromandel, the ocean and the smell of saltwater. I miss the sunrises and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/n8agrin/69861637/in/set-1504232/&quot;&gt;sunsets&lt;/a&gt;, the rainstorms and the hot days of February, the look of the sea in the morning, the power of the water and the serenity of the environment. Most of all i miss the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/n8agrin/69862078/in/set-1504232/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;STARS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transformation is an interesting thing, and I think that by going somewhere new, I was able to, eventually, transform myself into someone else. I survived and I learned about what I valued in life.  Perhaps most importantly I became happy, if at least for a time. I finally admitted my inner truths to myself. I let myself be mad about the things that made me mad and happy about the things that made me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experiencing that has changed my perspective on not just traveling, but living. I ended with, not a new sense  of self, but a truer sense of self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I am back in the US, with a new job and new ambitions, but ones that center around what excites me and makes me happy. Until last week I had never faced a day excited to go to work. Now I wake up knowing &lt;a href=&quot;http://chnm.gmu.edu&quot;&gt;someone is going to pay me&lt;/a&gt; to follow my passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll end this reflection with something I wrote the other day. I was researching some &lt;a href=&quot;http://ischool.berkeley.edu&quot;&gt;graduate school programs&lt;/a&gt; and I decided to come up with a list of objectives, a credo, so to speak, of how I see and aim to live my life. This isn’t necessarily a 180 from where I was a year, or a year and a half ago, but maybe it is a testament to my transition and to my fundamental shift in attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals in life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Be free, never have a cage.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Stay adventurous. Explore new places, things, traditions, and beliefs.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Challenge yourself, physically, mentally and spiritually. Never stop trying to push yourself to new limits.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Keep learning. Keep adding new knowledge about everything.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Explore and discover. Find &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NEW&lt;/span&gt; things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not ever be tied to a lifestyle, nothing physical is needed. Wants and desire are temporary fulfillment. True work is lasting fulfillment. Carry only the tools you need to accomplish this fulfillment, everything else is an anchor, a weight that limits your range in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel alive, keep asking &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Why?&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;December 30, 2009&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8211; Oakland, CA: Fixed some formatting&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>